Rafael Solis Utrilla

Full Stack Engineer

Mexico City, Mexico (GMT-5) (+52) 9612152373 rafasu8@gmail.com https://linkedin.com/rafasu

Full Stack Developer with more than 4 years of experience developing web and mobile applications, using different technologies such as React, React Native, Node, Java, AWS, Java and TypeScript. I have extensive experience in consulting, where I have had to work with several clients from different areas. I am currently looking for a remote position as Front-End or Full Stack Developer, however, I'm always open to new challenges.

EXPERIENCE

Globant —September 2021 - Current

Full Stack Dev.

• Creation of UI components for a cybersecurity company, managed the UI for 2 different applications and its design system that has different features such as data visualization components, data tables, etc..

Tech Stack: React, TypeScript, GraphQL, React Query, Gitlab, Storybook, Nx, Visx, AWS, Jest, Node, Redux.

Mobile Dev.

• Improved the performance for a mobile application that is used by more than 1 million users monthly. I also added new functionalities and connected the app to their new backend service.

Tech Stack: React Native, Redux, Redux Thunk, TypeScript, Firebase, Salesforce eCommerce, Jira

Full Stack Dev.

• Development for a POS system web app, modified microservices in Spring boot, testing and new features. **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Java, Spring boot, Jenkins, Enzyme, Jest, TypeScript

Tata Consultancy Services — November 2020 - September 2021 Full Stack Dev

• Created new UI features, modified endpoints, middlewares, and modified features all for internal applications used by more than 20k internal employees of an insurance company.

Tech Stack: React, Node, Express, Photoshop, CMS, Python, AWS

Deloitte. —May 2019 - September 2021

Full Stack Dev.

• Modernized the UX and added new functionality by deploying an internal web application used for a retail store's 400+ service agents. Improved testing coverage.

Tech Stack: React, Salesforce, Node, Express, Postgresql, Apex

Full Stack Dev.

 Improved mailing and filtering process of customers through the design and implementation of an email service for a bank that allows saving, filtering, and queries to its more than 20 million users. Addition of features for their Spring boot REST services.

Tech Stack: React, Mysql, AWS, Java, HTML, CSS, Spring boot, REST

Front End Dev.

• Improved the UX by recreating UI components for a No-code platform. Some of these components are very important and used as main parts in their platform that is used by thousands of customers.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Angular, Figma, Atlassian stack, Sass, Docker

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, **Frameworks Tools:** React, Spring boot, ExpressJS, Angular, Next

Data Base:; Postgresql, MySQL, MongoDb

Tools: Git, Jira, Confluence, Slack, Redux, React Query, Redux Thunk, GraphQL, AWS

Agile: Scrum, XP, Kanban **Languages:** English, Spanish.

EDUCATION

ITESM- Monterrey, Nuevo León. Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, May 2017

CERTIFICATIONS

Salesforce Administrator – Salesforce. 2019.
Salesforce Email Specialist – Salesforce. 2020.
Salesforce JavaScript Developer – Salesforce. 2022.